Motion motion. Okay motion and a second roll call please. Forster.
All right. Western. All right. Awesome. Vicky would you please come up and take a
seat at the party. Before we conduct the more business dated, are you ready to
swear in Vicky and also Doug and Brian because it's the first meeting in May.
If you guys have to take the order again. You can do it there or you can.
I'll also go right here on the ground. We'll get a photograph of the new. I'll make it very
simple. The author may or the author of the individual says I stay through
them and please actually stay the name because I've been told them. Other than that it's the
same boat for each of you and two of you have done this before in Jackie. I will tell you
on paper. It looks very brief but as you do it can seem somewhat long to the mayor's point
down. So I'll go ahead and begin. I'll ask each of you to get a raise or I can't please. I stay
your in. I'm ready. We have you done? We did that. And Vicky did you say anything? I'm ready to hear. Thank you.
You saw a very swear word for him. He saw a swear word for him. But I will support Obey of
the Fend. I will support Obey of the Fend. The Constitution of the United States.
The Constitution of the United States. The Constitution of the State of Oklahoma. The Constitution
of the State of Oklahoma. And I will not knowingly. And I will not knowingly. Receive directly or indirectly.
Any money or other valuable things. Any money or any other valuable things for the performance or
the performance or the performance of the non-performance. Any act or duty. Any act or duty.
Protecting to my office. Protecting to my office. Other than the compensation allowed by law.
Other than the compensation allowed by law. I further swear word for him. I further swear word for him.
But I will faithfully discharge according to the best of my ability. According to the best of my ability.
The duties of my office. The duties of my office. During such time as I am in member of the city council.
During such time as I am a member of the city council. And for you, big key of course, that's in word for.
And that's word for. And of course, that's word one. And the word of trustees. And the word of trustees.
Of the my and especially utility authority. Of the my and especially utility authority.
Of the city of my and the city of my and the help of the pitcher hands down.
And again, I just want to say thank you to Vicki for being willing to serve. We.
Seems we have critics at all levels of government but not very many.
Many people are willing to step up and I appreciate Vicki and I appreciate the continued service of the rest of the gentleman up here.
I remember full of his public input and unscheduled personal appearances,
or any one of the audience that wishes to address the council on any of the agenda items.
They're being known item five as a consent agenda staff is recommending item six through twelve for the consent agenda.
Are there any questions on any of those items?
There's not my or I'm like a motion print.
Okay, and a second.
Second.
Roll call please.
Johnson.
Forester.
Hi.
Lewis.
Weston.
Hi.
Thank you.
Item 13.
Resolution to Ways in his garage sale permit fee for the Miami News record annual citywide garage sale makes
7th, 2016 mark.
For the last 10 or so years the city of Miami and the Miami News record have teamed together
to host the citywide garage sale and the city has graciously suspended the the normal permit fee for that day only.
And we just asked that you do that again this year.
I think we have about 50 garage sales that are scheduled and 85 degree weather so should be a good day for all.
Okay.
Any questions?
If there are not.
I'll make a motion to wave the feed.
Do we have a second?
Second.
Roll call.
Should I.
Johnson.
Lewis.
I.
Forester.
Hey.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Item 14.
Resolution.
Repartments.
General policy.
As recommended by the parks board.
James.
Mr. Tom.
Hi.
Okay.
On item eight.
As you can see, it will be an increase for the ball fields.
For anyone hosting like tournaments or parties.
We've actually had birthday parties and stuff on ball fields before.
Okay.
So just to be clear, this has nothing to do with the normal recreation rise of our youth leagues.
It will not affect the MOUs that we have with our leagues at all.
Okay.
So if the MOUs, the leagues want to host a tournament or whatever.
That's falls under them so that won't affect.
Okay.
And the second item.
Be.
On item B.
With our stage, we always just had a verbal policy and never take it outside of city limits.
We've tried to take it to mind up before.
It was pretty rough.
So now we're want to written policy.
It's just for safety wise.
The link to the stage and the speed makes it.
It makes it pretty dangerous.
So we're just want to written policy now that the city manager can approve.
If it needs to just go outside of city limits.
And we have had some requests in the past.
We're just immediately outside the city limits.
And those were reasonable.
And in a lot of ways it would be intergovernmental cooperation.
Obviously, for taking it to row for something, we'll probably say no, but if it's just outside our city limits, we probably would try to help out by we normally would.
Any questions on that policy?
We have a motion, Ms. Lewis.
My move.
I have a second.
Second.
Oh, call.
Lewis.
I.
Western.
Forster.
Johnson.
I.
And you got your feet wet.
I know, Wellington.
I've你就.
I'm 15.
I'll have b c 16 72 contract with all of Universities for fixed school year.
15 16 audit.
Jill.
We send out a proposal asking for requests for products for the next few years at, we got back three
proposals.
We had a scoring system that was in your packet Lindsey and I scored the three proposals.
One of the most important...
or one of the most important,ash the team that pulled it back.
review, and that was the deciding factor on why we were making the recommendation we are.
We're not going to explain what that means, because what is peer review?
Well, that's where an outside company reviews their company for how well they perform their duties.
That, each one of the firms that gave a proposal use the exact same firm, so that was kind of nice.
So it was an Apple's comparison.
And so did you get a score?
You say each one of them uses the same firm.
So did that, that firm that that reviewed them,
gave them a score, and you took that into account?
No, they gave them a letter.
And kind of like our audit, we might be qualified or unqualified.
They got, well that's called, they deficiency, I'm sorry, they had deficiencies.
One company out of the three had two deficiencies, the other two had zero.
So they got a 15, so that was a pretty deciding factor.
We did talk a little bit with Crawford Associates about those deficiencies and had a pretty good discussion about that.
We are actually recommending the second, the middle company, the middle bid.
We have used these, this company before.
In the past actually right before Turner, we've used Turner for several years.
We used our, two or three years before that for two or three years.
It's really good to go to actually get a different auditor.
It does make you better.
It's kind of a pain because they ask you a whole set of different questions that you're not ready to answer.
But that's good.
It makes us better.
So we like, we like that because it does make us better.
So we're recommending this, the middle bid.
And David, this is a professional service as contract.
So it doesn't require a bid, correct, it just writes.
They put on RFP, which is appropriate for this type of work.
But I've always, from my part, suggested to staff that if you're not accepting the low bid, you should explain.
Why not?
Right.
Okay.
And, Dean, do you have any comments or, you know, after board timing?
I'm comfortable with the work that staff has done and I do want to emphasize that every
three to five years is a good idea to switch auditing firms.
When you consider the literal millions of tax dollars that come through this organization to ensure that we're
following policies, procedures, and fiscal responsibilities.
So, with that, I'm very comfortable that we're making that change right now.
We've gone through this process and we're having some fresh eyes to look at our books.
Is it just for one year or we want to look at this every year or every five years?
If it's in the five years, I've got a little bit of problem with it.
We asked them to bid out for five years and then we bring a contract to you each year.
And they're also, as the standard, well, relatively standard provision of the contract.
That they're entering the crystal pointed out.
Not that you expect this to happen.
You certainly hope it doesn't.
But on 30 days notice, you can always decide to withdraw.
Things weren't working out for such things.
For some reason.
I think related to Neil's question, there was a term in there about single use or single spotting.
A lot of things.
And explain that part to me.
That is our grants.
If we have over $750,000 grant money that runs through our organization in a year's time,
we have to also do a single audit.
We don't foresee one for 1516.
Well, but we hope we'll have one not to disobey each other.
For 1617?
We're going forward exactly.
Yeah.
Good problem to have.
If they were, then that's what the additional fee was on there for.
That's what that was about.
Okay.
So I want to make sure you guys saw that because that's how they put it in their proposals.
So I want to make it the same.
The farm that had the deficiencies.
Do you reach out to the firm?
Do you give them any explanation?
They get a copy of it from the peer reviewed.
That is, they gave it in their proposal.
They gave it in their proposal.
Do they give any updates on how they would correct what they consider,
what they was reviewed as deficiencies.
Would they have the opportunity to correct that?
Well, that's really an internal, kind of an internal audit.
So they tell you whether they'd fix it or not.
Well, yeah.
I didn't discuss that with any of the firm.
I suspect that there's there's compliance costs and depending on the size of the firm.
They may just decide that, you know, we're not going to do those two things.
And we understand that we get deemed for it and it may cost us some business.
In some cases and not in others.
Did the various firms know this was going to be discussed tonight?
Do not think so.
No, I don't think we notified any of them.
That was going to be on.
Well, the one that we're proposing does, they know, because we asked for an engagement letter.
Any other questions, Brian?
But we will give them letters after.
Any other questions?
Do we have a motion?
I'm okay with the fact.
We're going to look at this in another year, but just for 1.5 years, I'm not comfortable with that.
And that's not what you're supposed to do.
That's not what you're supposed to do.
And as I just said a little ball of doing, every 3 to 5 years, I think it's a good idea to change for us.
That's good.
I'm making a motion.
There will be a proof.
Okay.
And a second.
A second.
Roll call.
Johnson.
I.
Weston.
Okay.
Lewis.
I.
Shult.
All right.
I'm 16 new business in any business.
I'm 17 American Council Committee announcements in the announcements.
There you go.
Radio.
That's what you've been saying.
Well, you was.
Go ahead.
Radio.
Six and seven.
Don't forget.
This weekend.
Yes.
Tomorrow, we have groundbreaking for the animal shelter, which is that four o'clock I believe.
That I jump for.
And a lot for my fellow council members, maybe next council meeting or two, that we think about the naming of the shelter.
I put that on the agenda sometime, Dean.
And for the benefit of the population, the location is.
Just at the public court's billing, the south and public court's billing.
Where are these places?
Basically adjacent to where are the.
This is the old city with not the animal alliance.
Right.
But the old city.
On the truck.
And if anybody wants to make a donation, they can do so.
The community's foundation.
If Oklahoma is out of jail and just been in the mail.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay.
That's all I have.
Anything else?
Anyone?
All right.
City manager communication.
Okay.
I have three items here on our first off.
I just wanted to confirm that next week we're starting our budget sessions.
We'll be starting.
We have sessions scheduled right now on May 11th and 12 starting at 3 p.m.
So making sure and confirming with everybody that we've got it down.
Second thing.
I just want to point out that this is municipal clerks week.
So please be kind to a letter.
Well, we'll try to schedule a lunch for her sometime on that.
And then finally, and this is something that just happened a day.
And since we had a council meeting, I just thought it'd be a good opportunity to talk about what's going on.
You all see Ronnie in the audience and his lovely wife who's also a class of 75.
And we have to like Patty a whole lot more than Ronnie.
You know, Ronnie has let us know that he plans to retire on October.
And those are still the plans.
However, a number of projects that we've been working on internally, especially that are very important for the fired
department issues dealing with staffing with working.
with other departments, equipment, and all of that.
Ronny's had me work with Captain Wright, Robert Wright,
who's in the audience as well.
And had developed a good working relationship with him,
and we decided to go ahead and do an application internally
to see who would be interested in serving as our next fire chief.
And Robert has applied, and we talked today,
and we determined that we're going to be developing a transitional plan,
and he will be serving as our next fire chief
when Ronnie retires.
When that will be, because Ronnie keeps saying,
unless I fire you, or something like that,
you know, there'll probably be October, but it's going to be really nice
to have this transitional period,
especially going into budget season, and all that,
to be able not only to be working with Ronnie,
but working with Robert, not have that opportunity to work with,
and have a comfort level with him.
And I think it's going to be very good to have that kind of consistency
with the fire department, and even the right
and fallen members of the fire department, knowing
well in advance who their next chief is going to be.
I wish I'd had that circumstance and that opportunity,
when we did this with a police department.
I think if I had had a chance to work with Thomas Anderson,
a little bit closer at that time,
I probably would have come up with the same decision for him.
So if somebody's there going, why do you put a high tower to the ringer?
And Robert, that's the case.
And he's aware of this decision that I'm making, too,
and I've still been incredibly pleased with
his service right now as our police chief.
So these are two very important positions, one person.
It's just getting his feet on the ground,
it's doing a great job, and another person that I'm going to be able to work with.
And we have that type of consistency.
So I just wanted to make that announcement of what our plans are.
And just welcome on my board.
Congratulations both of you.
Yes, absolutely.
I know Ronnie's looking forward to some time off as his patty,
and Captain Wright, congratulations.
We know you're going to do an awesome job.
No, but you're seeing the bill.
Anything else?
Those are my comments, you're welcome.
Item 19 is Executive Session,
pursuant to $25 OS 3072 for discussing negotiations for employees
and representative employee group to win.
For turn, order a police lodge, number 121.
pursuant to $25 OS Section 307 E.
Do we have a motion to go into Executive Session?
All right, get a motion, man.
Second roll call.
All right.
Listen.
For a start.
Pop.
Loist.
Show.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Okay, nice to meet you.
See you.
Say what?
I'm second.
Oh.
I'm from German.
I'm going to go to the second.
So you're the second.
Thank you.
All right.
Okay, we are out of Executive Session.
It's 622.
Item 20 is a German.
We have a motion to adjourn.
Make the motion.
I will second that.
Oh no.
Forster.
Lewis.
I.
Wester.
Johnson.
Hi.
Thank you everyone.
Well that was.
I'm excited.
I got 20.
You can go to the next one.
It's still was your primary concern.
Yeah.
I just want to check.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.